<?xml version="1.0" ?><toc><docInfo path="unknown"><author>MA</author><topic>science</topic><filename>Science-2006-Massachusetts-Science and Technology Engineering .xml</filename><title>Massachusetts Science and Technology/Engineering Curriculum Framework</title><description>The 2006 Massachusetts Science and Technology/Engineering Curriculum Framework is the result of the contributions of many educators across the state to the 2001 Framework and, more recently, to the 2006 revision of the high school standards. Because of the broad-based, participatory nature of the revision process, this document cannot reflect all of the professional views of every contributor. It reflects instead a balanced synthesis of their suggestions.</description><version>http://purl.org/ASN/export/1.4.1</version><fileCreated>Mar 13 2008</fileCreated><created>2006</created></docInfo><docInfo path="unknown"><author>NY</author><topic>science</topic><filename>Science-1996-New York-Elementary Science, Intermediate Sc.xml</filename><title>Elementary Science, Intermediate Science, Living Environment, Earth Science, Chemistry, and Physics Core Curriculum</title><description></description><version>http://purl.org/ASN/export/1.4.1</version><fileCreated>Mar 13 2008</fileCreated><created>1996</created></docInfo><docInfo path="unknown"><author>NSES</author><topic>science</topic><filename>1995-National Science Education Standards (NSES)-Science-National Science Education Standard.xml</filename><title>National Science Education Standards</title><description></description><version>http://purl.org/ASN/export/1.4.0</version><fileCreated>Nov 26 2007</fileCreated><created>1995</created></docInfo><docInfo path="unknown"><author>CO</author><topic>science</topic><filename>Science-2007-Colorado-Model Content Standards Science.xml</filename><title>Colorado Model Content Standards Science</title><description>The Colorado Model Content Standards for Science represent what all Colorado students should know and be able to do in science as a result of their K-12 science education. Specific expectations are given for students completing grades K-2, 3-5, 6-8, and 9-12. These standards outline the essential level of science knowledge and skills needed by all Colorado citizens to participate productively in our increasingly technological society</description><version>http://purl.org/ASN/export/1.4.1</version><fileCreated>Mar 13 2008</fileCreated><created>2007</created></docInfo><docInfo path="unknown"><author>CO</author><topic>science</topic><filename>Science-1995-Colorado-Content Standards for Science.xml</filename><title>Colorado Model Content Standards for Science</title><description>The Colorado model standards presented here specify what all students should know and be able to do in science as a result of their school studies. Specific expectations are given for students completing grades K-4, 5-8, and 9-12. These standards reflect high expectations and outline the essential level of science knowledge and skills needed by all citizens to participate productively in our increasingly technological society. Some suggestions are also offered for those students who elect to extend their study of science beyond that specified in these content standards, based on their particular interests, motivation, career goals, and needs.</description><version>http://purl.org/ASN/export/1.4.1</version><fileCreated>Mar 13 2008</fileCreated><created>1995</created></docInfo></toc>