<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<table>

 

 

 

 

 <tr>

  <td>Search

  Topic</td>

  <td>Top 10 Results (Heading+website

  by clicking)</td>

  <td>Summary</td>

  <td>Key words</td>

 </tr>

 <tr>

  <td>learn

  about the contribution of Archimedes to the field of engineering physics</td>

  <td><a href="http://www.windows2universe.org/art_and_music/people_art_archive.html">Art Images of Scientists (title provided or enhanced by

  cataloger)</a></td>

  <td>This section of the Windows to

  the Universe website provides information and images about sculptures,

  paintings, drawings, and photographs of well-known scientists such as

  Archimedes, Aristotle, Copernicus, Marie Curie, Albert Einstein, Galileo, and

  ...</td>

  <td>Astronomy, History philosophy of

  science, History of science, Space sciences</td>

 </tr>

 <tr>

  <td/>

  <td><a href="http://www.fourmilab.ch/gravitation/foobar/">Bending

  Spacetime in the Basement</a></td>

  <td>This web page outlines an

  experiment to measure the effects of gravity for objects on the scale of

  kilograms. It begins by introducing the principles of gravity and comparing

  it against other forces. After demonstrating the weakness of the effects

  of...</td>

  <td>lassical Mechanics, General

  Relativity, Gravity, Physics, Science</td>

 </tr>

 <tr>

  <td/>

  <td><a href="http://www.lhup.edu/~dsimanek/museum/unwork.htm">The

  Museum of Unworkable Devices</a></td>

  <td>This site includes a collection

  of diagrams and pictures of devices, many patented, whose intended operations

  violate the laws of physics. The site focuses mostly on perpetual motion

  machines, but also has pages on simply impractical devices or artis...</td>

  <td>General Physics, History,

  History of science, Science, Science History, Science Physics, perpetual

  motion</td>

 </tr>

 <tr>

  <td/>

  <td><a href="http://mathforum.org/social/articles/npr-tape.html">Talk

  of the Nation, Science Friday</a></td>

  <td>An edited version of a radio

  program that aired on September 9, 1994. Science Friday host, Ira Flatow,

  interviewed guests Keith Devlin, Dean of Science at St. Mary's College, and

  William Dunham, math professor at Muhlenberg College.</td>

  <td/>

 </tr>

 <tr>

  <td/>

  <td><a href="http://ysm.research.yale.edu/article.jsp?articleID=291">Breakthroughs

  in the Water</a></td>

  <td>This article, featured in Yale

  Scientific magazine, describes a recent applications of fluid dynamics to

  swimsuit technology. The website provides an explanation of the forces acting

  on a human swimmer while moving through water and gives examples of...</td>

  <td>Dynamics of Fluids, Engineering,

  Fluid Mechanics, Other Sciences, Physics, Science, Speedo, olympics, swimmer,

  swimsuit</td>

 </tr>

 

</table>